A Guide to the Hunter-Garnett Families Papers, 1806-1889
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- Correspondence
  - Robert Mercer Taliaferro Hunter, Jr. to Maria (Hunter) Garnett, and poetry
    - 1857 Oct 19 (Box 2)
    - 1858 May 9 (Box 2)
    - 1858 May 20 (Box 2)
    - 1858 June 17 (Box 2)
    - 1859 Feb 20 (Box 2)
    - 1860 June 20 (Box 2)
    - [1860] Oct 29 (Box 2)
    - [1860] Dec (Box 2)
    - 1861 Feb 17 (Box 2)
    - 1861 Feb 26 (Box 2)
    - [1861] June (Box 2)
    - n.y. Nov 21 (Box 2)
    - Sunday (Box 2)
    - n.d. (Box 2)
    - n.d. (Box 2)
    - Poetry, "Midnight Musings" n.d. (Box 2)
  - Francis Mallory to Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
    - 1856 Dec 2 (Box 2)
    - John Marshall to James Mercer Garnett (Box 2)
    - 1830 Dec 17 (Box 2)
  - James Murray Mason to Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
    - 1850 Mar 16 (Box 2)
    - 1855 July 3 (Box 2)
  - Maria (Garnett) McGuire to Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
    - 1839 Mar 20 n.y. Oct 15 (Box 2)
  - Charles Fenton Mercer to Maria (Hunter) Garnett and Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
    - 1830 Feb 8 (Box 2)
    - 1844 Aug 30 (Box 2)
    - 1844 Mar 14 (Box 2)
    - 1849 Jan 23 (Box 2)
    - 1849 Dec 10 (Box 2)
  - Margaret Mercer to Ann and Nanette Garnett
    - 1813 Jan 8 (Box 2)
    - 1829 July 2 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Jan 1 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Jan 5 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Mar 14 (Box 2)
    - n.y. July 2 (Box 2)
    - n.y. July 17 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Sep 26 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Nov 20 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Dec 16 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Dec 19 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Dec 24 (Box 2)
    - n.d. (Box 2)
    - n.d. (Box 2)
  - Margaret Mercer to Maria (Hunter) Garnett
    - 1814 Feb 8 (Box 2)
    - [1820] Feb 16 (Box 2)
    - 1824 Aug 31 (Box 2)
    - 1830 Feb 25 (Box 2)
    - 1835 Oct 10 (Box 2)
    - 1837 Mar 5 (Box 2)
    - 1846 Jan 28 (Box 2)
    - 1846 Apr 27 (Box 2)
    - [n.y. ante-1820] (Box 2)
    - n.y. Mar 22 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Mar 26-27-28 (Box 2)
    - n.y. May 4 (Box 2)
    - n.y. May 10 (Box 2)
    - n.y. June 2 (Box 2)
    - (Box 2)
    - n.y. June 17 (Box 2)
    - n.y. July 3 (Box 2)
    - n.y. July 17 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Ayg 18 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Oct 26 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Oct 29 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Dec 9 (Box 2)
    - [n.y. post 1820] (Box 2)
    - n.y. Jan 12 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Feb 10 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Feb 20 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Feb 24 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Feb 25 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Apr 9 (Box 2)
    - n.y. May 17 (Box 2)
    - n.y. May 18 (Box 2)
    - n.y. May 29 (Box 2)
    - n.y. May 31 (Box 2)
    - n.y. June 3 (Box 2)
    - n.y. June 27 (Box 2)
    - n.y. July 1 (Box 2)
    - n.y. July 15 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Aug 6 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Aug 11 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Aug 19 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Sep 5 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Sep 19 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Sep 23 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Oct 11 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Oct 13 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Oct 23 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Nov 14 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Nov 22 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Nov 25 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Nov 26 (Box 2)
    - n.y. Dec 8 (Box 2)
    - n.d. (Box 2)
      [7 letters]
  - William Robert Mercer to Maria (Hunter) Garnett
    - 1869 Feb 11 (Box 3)
    - 1870 July 25 (Box 3)
    - 1870 Aug 4 (Box 3)
    - 1870 Nov 26 (Box 3)
    - 1872 Aug 5 (Box 3)
  - William Porcher Miles to Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett, with printed
    - 1860 Nov 13 (Box 3)
    - 1849 (Box 3)
      Pamphlet, Oration delivered before the Fourth of July Association, by Wm. Porcher Miles on the Fourth of July, 1849
    - 1852 (Box 3)
      Pamphlet, An Address delivered before The Alumni Society of The College of Charleston, on Commencement Day, March 30th, 1852, by Prof. William Porcher Miles, Anniversary Orator of the Society
    - (Box 3)
  - Lloyd Noland to Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
    - n.d. (Box 3)
  - Roger Atkinson Pryor to Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
    - 1857 Nov 2 (Box 3)
  - William J. Robertson to Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
    - 1842 Oct 19 (Box 3)
    - 1843 Jan 18 (Box 3)
    - 1843 June 9 (Box 3)
    - 1843 Aug 10 (Box 3)
    - 1846 July 7 (Box 3)
    - 1850 Sep 4 (Box 3)
    - 1850 Sep 17 (Box 3)
    - 1856 Dec 23 (Box 3)
    - 1854 Aug 26 (Box 3)
    - 1858 Jan 23 (Box 3)
  - Edmund Ruffin to Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
    - 1841 Jan 25 (Box 3)
    - 1850 Apr 22 (Box 3)
  - James A. Seddon to Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
    - 1856 Nov 16 (Box 3)
  - John Seddon to Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
    - 1856 July 5 (Box 3)
    - 1856 July 22 (Box 3)
  - Benjamin Silliman and Charles Upham Shepard to Charles Fenton Mercer Garnett
    - 1834 Apr 26 (Box 3)
  - Edwin A. and Mary Barton (Picton) Stevens to Maria (Hunter) Garnett
    - 1871 Aug 20 (Box 3)
    - n.y. Nov 19 (Box 3)
    - n.y. Nov 28 (Box 3)
  - John Taylor to James Garnett
    - 1806 June 26 (Box 3)
  - John R. Thompson to Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
    - 1850 Apr 17 (Box 3)
  - William Henry Trescott to Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
    - 1850 Dec 22 (Box 3)
    - 1851 Feb 16 (Box 3)
    - 1851 Mar 14 (Box 3)
    - 1851 May 15 (Box 3)
    - 1851 Nov 16 (Box 3)
    - 1852 May 6 (Box 3)
    - 1852 Nov 7 (Box 3)
  - J. Randolph Tucker to Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
    - 1843 Aug 29 (Box 3)
    - 1845 June 14 (Box 3)
    - 1851 Oct 8 1851 Dec 27 (Box 3)
    - 1854 Dec 23 (Box 3)
    - 1855 Apr 12 (Box 3)
    - 1855 Oct 24 (Box 3)
    - 1856 Nov 12 (Box 3)
  - Henry A. Wise to Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
    - 1855 Jan 23 (Box 3)
    - 1855 Apr 28 (Box 3)
    - 1855 June 19 (Box 3)
    - 1855 June 19 (Box 3)
    - 1855 July 26 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence
  - Miscellaneous Letters to Mary Picton (Stevens) Garnett
    - 1889 Aug 1 (Box 3)
    - n.y. Sep 4 (Box 3)
    - n.y. Oct (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Letters to Maria (Hunter) Garnett
    - 1846 Mar 30 (Box 3)
    - 1864 Apr 28 (Box 3)
    - 1866 Nov 20 (Box 3)
    - n.y. Feb 7 (Box 3)
    - n.y. Mar 27 (Box 3)
    - n.y. Mar (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Letters to Mary Eleanor (Dick) Garnett
    - 1810 Feb 23 (Box 3)
    - 1814 Oct 11 (Box 3)
    - 1818 May 26 (Box 3)
    - n.y. May (Box 3)
    - n.y. Oct 29 (Box 3)
- Correspondence of Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
  - Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett to Maria (Hunter) Garnett, [12 folders]
    - [1837-1843] (Box 3)
  - Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett to Maria (Hunter) Garnett, [27 folders]
    - [1845-1858] (Box 4)
  - Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett to Maria (Hunter) Garnett [1859-1864], [11 folders] (Box 5)
  - Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett to Robert Mercer Taliaferro Hunter (Box 5)
    - 1859 Apr 8 (Box 5)
    - 1861 Oct (Box 5)
    - Friday (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Personal Correspondence of Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett [1843-1852] (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Political Correspondence of Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett [1850-1860] (Box 5)
- Business Papers
  - Business Cards of Muscoe R. H. Garnett and Maria H. Garnett n.d. (Box 5)
  - Business Papers of Eliza L. Garnett [1842-1849] (Box 5)
  - Business Papers of Eliza L. Garnett: Account with H. B. and J. J. Gouldman [1844-1848] (Box 5)
  - Business Papers of Eliza J. Garnett: Account with Pitts and Sale [1841-1848] (Box 5)
  - Business Papers of Eliza J. Garnett: Account with John Saunders [1843-1849] (Box 5)
  - Business Papers of John Mercer Garnett [1830-1855] (Box 5)
  - Business Papers of John Mercer Garnett: Accounts for Medical Services [1843-1851] (Box 5)
  - Business Papers of Maria H. Garnett: Account with A. S. Garnett, Jr. and Company [1856-1871] (Box 5)
  - Business Papers of Maria H. Garnett: Account with William A. Baynham [1858-1860] (Box 5)
  - Business Papers of Maria H. Garnett: Account with Herbert, Hairston, and Company [1868-1873] (Box 5)
  - Business Papers of Maria H. Garnett: Account with Sale and Saunders [1868-1873] (Box 5)
  - Business Papers of Maria H. Garnett: Account with James S. Waters [1869-1870] (Box 5)
  - Business Papers of Maria H. Garnett: Account with William T. Outten and Company [1855-1859] (Box 5)
  - Business Papers of Muscoe R. H. Garnett: Account with Riggs and Company [1859-1861] (Box 6)
  - Business Papers of Muscoe R. H. Garnett: Account with Ward Brothers [1852-1859] (Box 6)
  - Business Papers of Muscoe R. H. Garnett: Account with E. Whitman [1850-1858] (Box 6)
  - Business Papers of Muscoe R. H. Garnett: Accounts with Contractors for work on "Elmwood" [1852-1854] (Box 6)
  - Business Papers of Muscoe R. H. Garnett and Maria H. Garnett: Accounts for Medical Services [1837-1873] (Box 6)
  - Business Papers of Muscoe R. H. Garnett and Maria H. Garnett [1837-1860], [9 folders] (Box 6)
  - Business Papers of Muscoe R. H. Garnett and Maria H. Garnett [1861-1873, n.d.], [7 folders] (Box 7)
  - Business Papers of Muscoe R. H. Garnett and Maria H. Garnett: Account with B. D. Pitts and Company [1838-1860], [2 folders] (Box 7)
  - Business Papers of Muscoe R. H. Garnett and Maria H. Garnett: Account with Baker and Brother [1852-1855] (Box 7)
  - Business Papers of Muscoe R. H. Garnett and Maria H. Garnett: Account with Capron and George [1852-1860], [2 folders] (Box 7)
  - Business Papers of Muscoe R. H. Garnett and Maria H. Garnett: Account with Cooke, Roy, and Jones [1867-1873] (Box 7)
  - Business Papers of Muscoe R. H. Garnett and Maria H. Garnett: Account with Farmers Bank of Virginia, Fredericksburg [1855-1861] (Box 7)
  - Business Papers of Muscoe R. H. Garnett and Maria H. Garnett: Account with Garnett and Pendleton [1855-1858] (Box 7)
  - Business Papers of Muscoe R. H. Garnett and Maria H. Garnett: Account with Henry P. Watts [1845-1855] (Box 7)
  - Business Papers of Grace Fenton Hunter [1835-1847] (Box 8)
  - List of receipts1847-1871 (Box 8)
  - Business Papers of Grace Fenton Hunter: Account with John M. Garnett [1824-1834] (Box 8)
  - Business Papers of James Hunter [1770-1778] (Box 8)
  - Estate of Grace Fenton Hunter [1844-1847] (Box 8)
  - Estate of John Mercer Garnett [1851-1860] (Box 8)
- Legal Papers
  - Legal Papers [1703-1866], [5 folders] (Box 8)
  - Legal Papers: Brooke vs. Dandridge [1853-1857] (Box 8)
  - Legal Papers: Essex County Deeds and Surveys re land of Marmaduke Thorp [1766-1767] (Box 8)
  - Legal Papers: Greenbrier County Deeds and Surveys re division of land dispute [1857-1858] (Box 8)
  - Legal Papers: Judgments on James M. Garnett and John M. Garnett [1856-1857] (Box 8)
  - Legal Papers: Lomax vs. Hunter [1870-1873] (Box 8)
  - Legal Papers: Maury vs. Garnett [(1855-1859)1869] (Box 8)
  - Legal Papers: Old Dominion Coal Company/Kanawha Coal Company [1857-1858] (Box 8)
  - Legal Papers: Pittsville Spring [1856] (Box 8)
- Topical
  - American Red Cross in France [1919-1920, n.d.], [3 folders] (Box 9)
  - "Calhoun on Government..." by Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett [1853] (Box 9)
  - Debating Societies Journals [1833-1834] (Box 9)
  - "The Elmwood Magazine" [1833, n.d.] (Box 9)
  - Elmwood: Papers re Victorian changes [1853] (Box 9)
  - Genealogy and History [1939-1970, n.d.] (Box 9)
  - "The Literary Box" [1829-1830] (Box 9)
  - Political Broadsides [1850s-1860s] (Box 9)
  - Political Issues [1842-1861] (Box 9)
    [material removed from scrapbook]
  - Political Issues: Newspapers Clippings on Slavery, Territorial Policies, and general politics [1857-1861, n.d.] (Box 9)
    [material removed from "Scrapbook on Political Issues...1857-1861, n.d."]
  - Political Issues: Government Documents on Slavery, Territorial Policies, and general politics [1858-1860, n.d.] (Box 9)
  - School Compositions of Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett, written in the Elmwood School [1830-1834] (Box 10)
  - School Papers of Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett [1830-1846, n.d.], [3 folders] (Box 10)
  - School Papers of Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett: Notes on Medieval Histories [ca. 1840s] (Box 10)
  - Sketches by Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett (Box 10)
  - Speeches of Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett [1847-1863] (Box 10)
  - Speeches of Robert Mercer Taliaferro Hunter [1854-1873] (Box 10)
  - Travel Journal of Portugal (on letterhead "Legation of the United States, Lisbon") [1887 Jan-Feb] (Box 10)
  - "The Union, Past and Future: How it Works, and How to Save It" by M. R. H. Garnett [1850] (Box 10)
  - Virginia General Assembly Issues [1849-1860] (Box 10)
- Bound Volumes
  - Daybook and Memorandums respecting the affairs of James Mercer, Mercer Garnett, administrator [containing slave lists and evaluations] [1795-1799] (Box 11)
  - Daybook for Estate of William Hunter [containing lists of slaves and clothing/shoe allotments [1786-1795, 1830-1852] (Box 11)
  - House of Representatives [lists of committees membership], kept by M. R. H. Garnett [1858] (Box 11)
  - The Independent Columbian Debating Society minutes and debate notes, with court fees, 1819-1820, kept by Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett [1825] (Box 11)
  - Scrapbook of newspapers and essays on U. S. resolutions, kept by Muscoe R. H. Garnett [1789(1842-1855)] (Box 11)
  - Scrapbook on Political Issues: Slavery, Territorial Policies, and general politics, 1857-1861, n.d. (Box 11)
- Oversize Items
  - Indenture between Thomas and Dorothy Edmondson, Essex County, of the one part and James Garnett, Essex County, of the other part re tract of land in Essex County 1743 Oct 2 (Box 11)
  - Indenture between John Long, Essex County, of the one part, and John Hughes, King George County, of the other part re tract of land in Essex County 1745 Sep 16 (Box 11)
  - Indenture between Thomas Thornton, Gloucester County, of the one part and Bernard Noel, Essex County, of the other part re tract of land in Essex County 1746 Apr 15 (Box 11)
  - 1765 Nov 20 (Box 11)
    Indenture between Bernard and Sarah Gaines, Essex County, of the one part and Muscoe Garnett, Essex County, of the other part re tract of land in Essex County
  - Indenture between James M. Garnett of the first part and John M. Garnett of the second part and Robert P. Waring of the third part re tract of land in Essex County 1824 Mar 1 (Box 11)
  - Survey of land owned by the Old Dominion Coal Company/Kanawha Coal Company n.d. (Box 11)